Finding Aid for the Richard Ashcraft Papers LSC.0495
UCLA Library Special Collections
Richard Ashcraft papers
circa 1966-1995
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ashcraft, Richard
LSC.0495
16.0 linear feet (24 boxes)
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Estate of Richard Ashcraft.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942303353606533
Biographical History
Richard Elden Ashcraft was born in San Francisco, California, Sept. 26, 1938; BA, Harvard, 1960, MA (1961) and Ph.D (1966), Univ. of CA, Berkeley; was the recipient of numerous awards including the American Political Science Assn. Congressional Fellowship for 1963-64; joined the Political Science Department, UCLA (1965-ca. 1995) where his teaching interests included the history of political thought, Marxism theory, and methodology in the social sciences; published several books, articles, and essays on political theory including Revolutionary politics and Locke's two treatises of government (1985) and Locke's Two treatises of government (1985); he died November 1, 1995.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of materials related to the career of political science professor, Richard Ashcraft. Includes research files and notes, publications, reviews, lecture notes, and course syllabi and papers. Research includes material on various political science related topics including John Locke and John Stuart Mill.
- "Marx Exegesis Collected Works", undated (Box 1)
- "Chapter 1", undated (Box 1)
- 4 card file boxes, Ashcraft's note cards, undated (Box 1)
- "Mill Research Materials", undated (Box 2)
- Ashcraft's note cards (Box 2)
- "Various Older Research Notes" (Box 3)
- Ashcraft- authored reviews, undated (Box 3)
  Scope and Contents
  6 folders
- Photograph, 1984 (Box 3)
- Locke Bibliography, 1904 - 1987 (Box 3)
  4 notepads
- Research Files
  - "Journal of the History of Political Thought", undated (Box 4)
  - "Puritanism", undated (Box 4)
  - "Reformation", undated (Box 4)
  - "Milton", undated (Box 4)
  - "Elizabethan England", undated (Box 4)
  - "English Revolution, etc.", undated (Box 4)
- Locke card files, undated (Box 4)
- Dissertations
  - Barrow, Clyde W., 1984 (Box 4)
  - Gavre, William Mark, 1978 (Box 4)
  - King, Paul Edward, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Sarvasy, Wendy Joy, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Wood, Ellen Meiksins, 1970 (Box 4)
- Harvard Class of 1960 anniversary reports, 1985, 1995 (Box 4)
- UCLA Lecture Notes, undated (Box 4)
- Master reprint file (Ashcraft authored), circa 1968-1995 (Box 5)
- Publication file, 1988 - 1989 (Box 5)
- Ashcraft publications, reviews, conferences, etc., circa 1966 - 1986 (Box 6)
- Papers, book reviews, etc., circa 1974 - 1994 (Box 7)
- Ashcraft conference presentations, circa 1966 - 1993 (Box 7)
- Requests for books, articles, undated (Box 7)
- Ashcraft publications (reverse chronological order), 1990 - 1994 (Box 8)
- UCLA Lecture notes, undated (Box 8)
- UCLA Lecture notes, undated (Box 9)
- "Other's lectures", undated (Box 9)
  1 folder
- Research notes and files (alphabetical order): 18th century England - Burke, undated (Box 9)
- Research notes and files: Camus - Marxism, undated (Box 10)
- "Letters from Boulogne" re: Vietnam War, undated (Box 10)
- Research notes and files: Mark - Wells, undated (Box 11)
- Miscellaneous files, undated (Box 11)
- Ashcraft research
  - J.S. Mill, undated (Box 12)
    1 box of cards
  - General research, undated (Box 12)
    1 box of cards; includes British Library call slips
  - Hooker, Marx, Lenin, and Engels, undated (Box 13)
  - Mannheim, Karl, undated (Box 13)
  - Locke, John, undated (Box 14)
- Notes, correspondence, undated (Box 14)
- Miscellaneous files, undated (Box 14)
- Miscellaneous research files, undated (Box 15)
- Ashcraft undergraduate and graduate course syllabi, notes and papers, circa 1958 - 1966 (Box 16)
  9 folders
- B.A. honors thesis, 1960 (Box 16)
- Early papers, undated (Box 16)
- "Grad work", undated (Box 16)
- Notes, undated (Box 16)
  3 notebooks
- Ph.D. dissertation typescript, circa 1966 (Box 16)
  4 folders
- Sorel notes and translation, undated (Box 16)
- "Chapter Four" typescript, undated (Box 16)
- "Chapter Five" typescript, undated (Box 16)
- Existentialism: Philosophy and Psychotherapy typescript, undated (Box 16)
- Miscellaneous materials, undated (Box 16)